Hey there, super sleuths!
こんにちは、探偵たち！
Get your detective gear ready, because you've just been assigned a brand new case.
探偵道具を準備して、 新しい事件があなたに任されました。
Today, we're becoming English detectives, and our mission?
今日は英語の探偵になり、 私たちのミッションは？
To crack the code on asking questions about what's happening right now!
今何が起こっているかを 質問する方法を解明することです！
Okay, so imagine this.
では、想像してみてください。
You're on a video call with your friend in California.
カリフォルニアの友達と ビデオ通話をしています。
You're talking about the latest anime, and then, all of a sudden, crash!
最新のアニメについて話していると、 突然、ドン！という音がします。
You hear this huge noise from their room.
何が起こったのか知りたいですよね？
You gotta know what's going on, right?
最初に何を聞きますか？
What's the very first question you ask?
完璧な質問を考えましょう。
Let's figure out the perfect thing to say.
あなたの公式ミッションは、 受け入れるなら、
So here's your official mission, should you choose to accept it?
「今何をしているか」を 尋ねる達人になることです。
You're going to become a master of the right now question.
これは、相手が 何をしているかを知るために 非常に重要なスキルです。
This is a super important detective skill for figuring out what someone is doing at the
今、話している瞬間に 何をしているかを知るための。
exact moment you're talking to them.
良い探偵は道具を知っている必要がありますよね？
Now every good detective has to know their tools, right?
新しいガジェットを手に入れる前に、 基本的な道具を確認しましょう。
So before we get any cool new gadgets, let's do a quick check on the basic equipment
これは簡単な復習になるはずです。
you've already got in your investigation kit.
では、シンプルな例から始めましょう。 あなたはお腹が空いています。
This should be a nice easy review.
これは感情、状態を表しています。 簡単ですね。
Okay, let's start with something really simple. You are hungry.
でも、これについて尋ねたい場合は？
This just describes a feeling, a state of being. Easy enough.
どうやって文を質問に変えますか？
But what if we want to ask about it?
こうやって、B動詞を使います。 この場合は「are」を前に持ってきます。
How do we flip this from a statement into a question?
「あなたはお腹が空いています」という文が、 「あなたはお腹が空いていますか？」に変わります。
Just like that, we just take the B verb, in this case R, and we pop it right at the
これができること、分かりますか？
front.
これはあなたのツールキットにある 重要なスキルです。
The statement, you are hungry, instantly becomes the question, are you hungry?
これを探偵ハンドブックの ルール1として覚えておきましょう。
You already know how to do this, see?
状態について尋ねるとき、 例えば「幸せ」や「お腹が空いている」、
It's a key skill you already have in your toolkit.
「忙しい」といった状態のときは、 B動詞が常に文の先頭に来ます。
So let's lock this in as rule number one in your detective handbook.
分かりましたか？ 基本はしっかり身についています。
Anytime you're asking about a state of being, you know, a condition like being happy or
さて、次は楽しい部分、 ハイテクガジェットのアップグレードです。
hungry or busy, that B-verb always moves to the front of the line to lead the investigation.
新しい力、行動について尋ねる能力を 解放しましょう。
Got it? All right, toolkit checked. You've got the basics down cold.
このスライドを見てください。 新しいガジェットが動いています。
Now it's time for the really fun part, a high-tech gadget upgrade.
左側の質問「彼女は忙しいですか？」は 彼女の状態を尋ねています。
Let's move on, because we're about to unlock a new power, the ability to ask about actions.
でも右側を見てください。「彼女は勉強していますか？」 これは違います。
Now check this out. This slide shows our new gadget in action.
「勉強する」は状態ではなく、 今まさに行われている行動です。
Look at the left side.
その違い、分かりますか？ とても重要です。
The question, is she busy, asks about her condition. It's a state.
では、この新しいガジェットはどう機能するのでしょう？
But look over on the right. Is she studying? Now that's different.
実は、非常にシンプルな三ステップの 公式があります。
Studying is in a state. It's an action that's happening right now.
まず、古典的なB動詞「is」「am」「are」を使います。
You see that difference? It's super important.
次に、主語を加えます。 つまり、話している相手です。
So how does this new gadget work?
そして、最後の秘密の材料です。
Well, it's a really simple three-step formula.
動作動詞に「ing」を付け加えます。
First, you start with your good old B-verb, is, am, or are.
これが全てのコツです。 実際の例で試してみましょう。
Second, you add the subject, you know, who you're talking about.
友達にメッセージを送って、 彼の兄が暇か知りたいとします。
And third, here's the secret ingredient.
「あなたの兄はSplatoonをしていますか？」と聞けます。 公式が見えますか？
You add the action verb, but with ing at the end.
「is」がB動詞、 「あなたの兄」が主語、
That's the whole trick. Let's try it out with a real example.
「playing」がING動詞、 今何が起こっているかを尋ねるのに最適です。
Maybe you're texting a friend and you want to know if their brother is free.
もう一つの例はどうですか？
You could just ask, is your brother playing Splatoon? See the formula?
友達が電話をセットアップしているのを見て、 リングライトを出しているとき、
is, that's the B verb, plus your brother, the subject,
「今、TikTokの動画を作っていますか？」と聞けます。 その瞬間にぴったりの質問です。
plus playing, the ING verb, perfect for asking
実際、これがアメリカの人々が 普段話したりメッセージを送ったりする方法です。
what's happening this very second. Or how about this one?
目の前で何が起こっているかを尋ねるのです。 さて、探偵さん。
You see your friends setting up their phone,
あなたは「今何をしているか」の質問に 成功しました。
Mission accomplished? Mm, not quite.
ミッションは成功？うーん、まだだね。
Now you need to understand the intel you get back.
今度は、戻ってきた情報を理解する必要がある。
Let's learn how to understand the answers.
答えを理解する方法を学ぼう。
And here it is, the biggest secret of this entire mission.
これがこのミッションの最大の秘密だ。
You ready for this? The way you answer these new action questions
準備はいい？新しいアクションの質問への答え方は
is exactly the same as the basic questions
基本的な質問と全く同じだ。
you already know how to answer. No new rules to learn.
新しいルールを学ぶ必要はない。
It's like a totally free upgrade. And this table proves it.
まるで完全無料のアップグレードだ。これが証明している。
Look, if you ask, Is he studying?
例えば、「彼は勉強している？」と聞けば、
The answer is just yes he is or no he isn't.
答えは「はい、している」か「いいえ、していない」。
If you ask are they studying? It's yes they are or no they aren't.
「彼らは勉強している？」なら、「はい、している」か「いいえ、していない」。
It's the exact same pattern you already know.
全く同じパターンだ。
It really is a free upgrade. So cool right?
本当に無料のアップグレードだ。すごいよね？
Alright Detective, you have your upgraded gadget and you know how to decode the intel.
さあ、探偵。アップグレードされた道具を持って、情報を解読できる。
There's only one thing left to do.
残ることは一つだけ。
It's time for your final field test to prove you've got the skills.
スキルを証明するための最終フィールドテストの時間だ。
Get ready! Okay, here's your first case.
準備はいい？最初のケースだ。
The words are all scrambled up, like a secret code.
言葉がすべて混ざっている、秘密のコードのように。
Can you unscramble this clue to form a perfect right now question?
この手がかりを解読して、完璧な「今」質問を作れる？
The words are watching, you, TV, are, now.
言葉は「見ている」「あなた」「テレビ」「今」だ。
Take a second. What's the question?
少し考えて。質問は何？
And the correct answer is, are you watching TV now? Fantastic work!
正しい答えは「あなたは今テレビを見ていますか？」素晴らしい！
You put the B verb first, then the subject, then the ING verb.
B動詞を最初に、その後に主語、ING動詞だ。
Case closed. Excellent. Let's keep this momentum going.
ケースは終了。素晴らしい。勢いを続けよう。
Here's your second and final case, the clues are sleeping, John, is, now, put them in the
次のケース、最後のケースだ。手がかりは「寝ている」「ジョン」「今」だ。
right order. Quick, what's the question? And you've done it again.
正しい順序に並べて。早く、質問は何？
The question is, is John sleeping now?
質問は「ジョンは今寝ていますか？」
You've totally mastered the formula.
完全に公式をマスターしたね。
You are officially a certified English detective. Awesome job.
あなたは正式に認定された英語探偵だ。素晴らしい仕事。
And with that, your mission is a complete success.
これで、あなたのミッションは完全成功だ。
Go ahead, give yourself a pat on the back, Detective.
さあ、自分を褒めてあげて、探偵。
You have officially cracked the case of the right now questions and added a seriously
あなたは「今」質問のケースを解決し、
powerful new tool to your collection.
強力な新しいツールを手に入れた。
So let's go over your final mission debrief. Key takeaway number one.
では、最終ミッションの振り返りをしよう。重要なポイントその1。
To ask about what's happening now, you use that formula, bverb plus subject plus
今何が起きているかを尋ねるには、その公式を使う。
verbing.
B動詞＋主語＋動詞ING。
Two, the answers are super simple and use the rules you already know.
2つ目、答えはとてもシンプルで、既に知っているルールを使う。
And most importantly, remember, this isn't just for some test, this is your key to
そして最も重要なのは、これはテストのためだけではなく、
more natural text messages, clearer video calls, and finally understanding what's actually
より自然なテキストメッセージや、クリアなビデオ通話、
happening in your favorite American movies and TV shows.
お気に入りのアメリカの映画やテレビ番組で何が起きているかを理解するための鍵だ。
Your training is complete.
あなたのトレーニングは完了した。
You've got the skill, you've got the knowledge, and you are ready for the field.
スキルも知識も持って、フィールドに出る準備ができている。
So my final question to you is this.
では、最後の質問です。
Who are you going to text first to try out your new detective powers?
新しい探偵の力を試すために、誰に最初にメッセージを送る？
Go on, the case is yours.
さあ、ケースはあなたのものだ。